[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So far in this module, we've discussed learning decision tree, but
قد ناقشنا حتى الآن في هذه الوحدة، تعلم شجرة القرارات،
we only used what's called categorical data inputs or features.
ولكننا استخدمنا فقط ما يعرف بمدخلات البيانات الفئوية أو سماتها.
So, we looked at, credit could be poor, fair, or excellent.
فكنا ننظر إلى احتمالية أن يكون الائتمان لدينا سيئًا أو جيدًا أو ممتازًا.
However, if you look at income, that's what's called a real value feature.
ومع ذلك، إذا نظر إلى الدخل، فهذا ما يعرف بسمة القيمة الحقيقية.
It has continuous possible values.
حيث إن لديها قيمًا محتملة متتالية.
So 105,000, 73,000, 69,000, and so on.
مثل، 105000 و73000 و69000 وهكذا.
So the question is how do you build a decision tree with this kind of input?
لذا فالسؤال هو، كيف يمكنك إنشاء شجرة قرارات باستخدام هذا النوع من الإدخال؟
One natural approach is to just treat income or
يتمثل أحد النهج الطبيعية ببساطة في معالجة الدخل
the continuous valued feature by of the categorical data.
أو سمة القيمة المتتالية كما تعاملنا مع البيانات الفئوية.
So let's take that root nulled with 40 datapoints and just split on income.
لذا، دعونا نأخذ هذا الجذر المفرغ إلى 40 نقطة بيانات ونقسمه وفقًا للدخل.
And see what happens.
ونرى ما سيحدث.
Well, there is one datapoint with income of $30,000.
حسنًا، هناك نقطة بيانات واحدة مع دخل يساوي 30000.
There's one datapoint income of $31,400.
ونقطة بيانات واحدة بدخل 31400.
There's one datapoint with income $39,500 and so on.
وهناك نقطة بيانات واحدة بدخل 39500 وهكذا.
And it turns out that the nodes that we get out of them
واتضح أن العقد التي نحصل عليها من خلالهم
basically only have one datapoint in them.
هي في الأساس لديها نقطة بيانات واحدة بهم.
And this can be really, really bad.
وهذا الأمر قد يكون سيئًا للغاية.
When you have very few data points in the intermediate node in the decision tree
فعندما يكون لديك عدد قليل للغاية من نقاط البيانات في العقدة المتوسطة بشجرة القرارات،
you're very prone to overfitting.
فأنت عرضة للإفراط في المطابقة.
Very prone to make predictions you cannot trust.
أنت عرضة للقيام بتنبؤات لا يمكنك الوثوق بها.
So, for example, if you look here you'd predict in this case
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا نظرت هنا فستقوم بالتنبؤ في هذه الحالة
that if you're income is $30,000, this is definitely a risky loan,
أن إذا كان الدخل يساوي 30000، فإن هذا القرض حتمًا يشكل مخاطرة،
but if you're income is $31,400 is definitely a safe loan,
ولكن إذا كان الدخل 31400 فإنه يعتبر قرضًا آمنًا بالتأكيد.
however if your income is now 39,500, you're back to risky.
على الرغم من أنه إذا كان الدخل 39500 فإنك ستعود مرة أخرى إلى حيث يكون القرض يشكل مخاطرة.
So [LAUGH] it's risky, safe, risky, which doesn't make any sense.
لذا، فستجد مخاطرة ثم أمانًا ثم مخاطرة، والذي لا ينطوي على أي معنى.
Do you trust it?
هل تثق في ذلك؟
I wouldn't.
ما كنت لأفعل.
And so the question is, how do we deal with this real valued features.
لذا فالسؤال هو، كيف نتعامل مع سمات القيم الحقيقية هذه؟
As a very natural alternative, we can work on threshold splits.
كبديل طبيعي لذلك، يمكننا العمل على تقسيمات الحد الأدنى.
And these are simply picking a threshold on the value
وهذا ببساطة عبارة عن اختيار حد أدنى لقيمة
of that continuous valued feature, so let's say 60,000.
هذه السمة ذات القيم المتتالية، لذا لنفترض أنه 60000.
And for the left side of that split will put all the data points have income
وعلى الجانب الأيسر من هذا التقسيم سنضع كل نقاط البيانات التي لديها دخل
lower than $60,000, and on the right,
أقل من 60000، وعلى الجانب الأيمن،
will put all the data points have incomes higher than or equal to $60,000.
سنضع كل نقاط البيانات التي لديها دخل أعلى من أو يساوي 60000.
And as we can see, we have a subset of the data here, income higher than $60,000.
وكما نرى، فإن لدينا مجموعة فرعية من البيانات هنا ذات دخل أعلى من 60000.
And for those we have many data points there.
وبالنسبة لهذه المجموعات، فإن لدينا العديد من نقاط البيانات.
So, it's a lot less risk of over fitting and we see that 14 of
لذا، فهناك مخاطرة أقل للتعرض إلى الإفراط في المطابقة، ونلاحظ أن هناك 14 منهم
them have our safe laws so probably predict a safe there.
لديهم قروض آمنة، لذا ربما أقوم بالتنبؤ بناءً على الأمان.
Well, 13 will risk you on the $60,000 so maybe you'll predict those as risks.
حسنًا، وهناك 13 نقطة تشكل مخاطرة بالنسبة للدخل 60000، لذا قد يمكنك إجراء التنبؤ بناءً على نسبة المخاطرة.
So this is a very natural kind of split that we might want to do
وهذا يعتبر نوعًا طبيعيًا للتقسيم الذي قد نرغب في القيام به
with continuous value data.
فيما يتعلق بالبيانات ذات القيم المتتالية.
Let's now take a moment to visualize what happens when we do this kind of
دعونا نتوقف لحظة الآن لتصور ما يمكن أن يحدث عندما نقوم بهذا النوع من
threshold split.
التقسيم وفقًا للحد الأدنى.
So for example, I've laid out my data income into this line here that
على سبيل المثال، فقد قمت بوضع بيانات الدخل في هذا الخط هنا
ranges from 10,000 to 120, and if we pick a threshold split of 60,000 and
والذي يتراوح بين 10000 إلى 120000، وإذا قمنا باختيار تقسيم الحد الأدنى ليكون 60000،
we say everything on the left of the split has income less that $60,000 we're
فإننا نقول أن كل ما يوجد على يسار التقسيم لديه دخل أقل من 60000
going to predict to be risky loans.
وأننا سنجري التنبؤ بناءً على أنها قروض تشكل مخاطرة.
Everything to the right has income higher than $60,000 we're going to predict those
وكل ما يوجد على اليمين لديه دخل أعلى من 60000 وسنقوم بإجراء التنبؤ عليهم
as being safe loans.
وفقًا لأنهم قروض آمنة.
Now let's supposed that we have two continuous value to features.
والآن دعونا نفترض أن لدينا اثنتين من السمات ذات قيم متتالية.
We have income in the y axis and we have age in the x axis, and
ويتم تمثيل الدخل على المحور y وتمثيل العمر على المحور x،
let's see what happens here.
لذا، دعونا نرى ما يحدث هنا.
And you'll see there are some positive and negative examples laid out in 2D.
ستلاحظ أن هناك بعض الأمثلة الموجبة والسالبة موضحة في شكل ثنائي البعد.
Another thing that's interesting is that you see that
والشيء الآخر المثير للاهتمام، أنه يمكنك ملاحظة أن
older people with higher incomes tend to be safe loans, but
الأشخاص كبار السن ممن لديهم دخل أعلى يميلون إلى تمثيل القروض الآمنة،
also younger people that may have lower incomes, those might also be
ولكن أيضًا الأشخاص الأصغر ممن لديهم دخل أقل، يمكنهم أيضًا أن
safe loans because those people may make money over time, let's say.
يمثلوا شكل آمن للقروض، حيث إن هؤلاء الأشخاص يمكنهم جني المال بمرور الوقت، لنفترض ذلك.
So we might look at this state and decide to split on age first.
لذا، قد ننظر إلى هذه الحالة ونقرر التقسيم بناءً على العمر أولًا.
And if we split on age, let's say age equals 38, we'll see that for
وإذا قمنا بالتقسيم بناءً على العمر، ولنفترض أن العمر يساوي 38، فسنلاحظ أن
the folks that are younger than 38,
الأشخاص الأقل من 38،
on average, more of them have risky long, so you might predict risky.
في المتوسط، يكون معظمهم لديه قروض تشكل مخاطرة، لذا فيمكن التنبؤ وفقًا للمخاطرة.
But for the folks that have age greater than 38,
ولكن بالنسبة للأشخاص ممن هم أعلى من 38،
we have more safe loans than risky.
فإن لدينا قروضًا آمنة أكثر من التي تشكل مخاطرة.
So we might predict safe.
وبالتالي، يمكن التنبؤ بناءً على الأمان.
Now to the next split in our decision tree.
والآن، لننتقل إلى التقسيم التالي في شجرة القرارات لدينا.
We might choose to split for the folks that have age greater than 38 we
يمكن أن نختار أن يتم التقسيم على أساس الأشخاص ذوي العمر الأكبر من 38،
might split on the income and ask whether this income greater than $60,000 or not.
ويمكننا التقسيم على أساس الداخل، ما إذا كان أكبر من 60000 أو لا.
And if it is, we put a split there.
وإذا كان كذلك، فنضع فاصلًا هنا.
And we'll see that the point below Income below $60,000
وسنلاحظ في النقطة بالأسفل أن الدخل أقل من 60000،
even the higher age might be negative, so might be predicted negative.
حتى بالنسبة للأشخاص الكبار، يمكنه أن يكون سلبيًا، لذا قد يمكن التنبؤ وفقًا للسلبية.
So let's take a moment to visualize the decision tree we've learned so far.
دعونا نتوقف لحظة لتصور شجرة القرارات التي تعلمناها حتى الآن.
So we start from the root node over here and we made our first split.
لذا، سنبدأ من عقدة الجذر هنا، وسنقوم بعمل أول تقسيم.
And for our first split, we decide to split on age.
وفيما يخص التقسيم الأول، فقد قررنا إجراء التقسيم على أساس العمر.
And the two possibilities we looked at were,
وكان الاحتمالان اللذان نظرنا إليهما
is the age smaller
العمر ما إذا كان أصغر
than 38 or is the age greater than or equal to 38.
من 38 أو العمر أكبر من أو يساوي 38.
So that was our first threshold split.
وكان هذا أول تقسيم وفقًا للحد الأدنى.
And for those with age smaller than 38, let's say that we stopped right here,
بالنسبة لهؤلاء ممن هم أصغر من 38 عامًا، لنفترض أننا توقفنا هنا
we'd see that there's five risky and three safe.
فسنلاحظ أن هناك خمسة احتمالات للمخاطرة وثلاثة للأمان.
So we'd predict risky.
لذا، فسنجري التنبؤ على أساس المخاطرة.
So that might be our leaf here.
ويمكن أن يكون ذلك الورقة التي لدينا.
And for age greater than 38 we took another split, which was on income.
وبالنسبة للعمر الأكبر من 38، فقد أجرينا تقسيمًا آخر وكان على أساس الدخل.
And we just ask ourselves is the income Is it
وسنسأل أنفسنا ببساطة، هل هذا الدخل
less than 60,000 or is it greater than or equal to 60,000?
أقل من 60000 أو هو أكبر من أو يساوي 60000؟
Now for the ones that have income greater than or
والآن، بالنسبة للأشخاص الذين لديهم دخل أكبر من
equal to 60,000 in age greater than 38 we predicted those were safe loans.
أو يساوي 60000 وعمر أكبر من 38، فسنجري التنبؤ على هؤلاء بناءً على القروض الآمنة.
While the ones that had age greater than 38 and
في حين أن الأشخاص الذي لديهم عمر أكبر من 38
income less than $60,000, we predicted those to be risky loans.
ودخل أقل من 60000 فسنجري التنبؤ عليهم بناءً على المخاطرة التي تشكلها القروض.
And this is an example for the tree where we're making
وهذا هو المثال حول شجرة القرارات حيث نقوم
these binary splits on the data for the continuous variables.
بعمل هذه التقسيمات الثنائية على البيانات للمتغيرات المستمرة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]